# Neeraj Kumar

# **Data Analyst Professional**

Email: Neeraj.Kumar02a@gmail.com; Phone: +91 7483610904, +91 7022135391

**Linkedin:** linkedin.com/in/neeraj-kumar-5a40a719b/ **Github**: github.com/Neeraj02a

# **Targeting assignments in Data Analysis**

Data Analyst with 4+ years of experience interpreting and analyzing data in order to drive successful business solutions. Proficient knowledge in statistics, mathematics, and analytics. Excellent understanding of business operations and analytics tools for effective analyses of data.

#### **Technical (IT) Skills**

**Data Management:** Database Design & Management, Data Quality Assessment, Data Analysis, Pattern & Trend Identification, Visualization of Data Insight.

**Computer Science:** Python [Django, Flask, Panda, NumPy, SciPy], Tableau, Azure, MY SQL, Microsoft Excel VBA, Advance Microsoft Excel functions, Java, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Unix, C, C++, System Administration, Troubleshooting.

**Research:** Data Analytics Research Methods, Survey Creation.

### **Work Experience**

#### **DATA ANALYST**

Cognizant Technology Solutions (December 2019 – Present)

- Converted data into actionable insights by predicting and modeling future outcomes.
- Utilized MS SQL, Azure, data warehousing programs, Tableau and other dashboard/visualization toolsets for data intelligence and analysis.
- Proposed solutions to improve system efficiencies and reduce total expenses.

#### **DATA ANALYST**

Cognizant Technology Solutions (January 2018 – November 2019)

• Identified, analyzed and executed new and potential products, services, markets and advertising opportunities.

- Collected and analyzed data on established and prospective customers, competitors and marketing channels and sources.
- Prepared reports that interpret consumer behavior, market opportunities and conditions, marketing results, trends and investment levels.
- Utilized Google Analytics and implemented new scripts that increased performance by 25%.
- Successfully adhered to company data governance standards receiving the "Star employee of the first quarter 2019".

#### **DATA ANALYST**

Cognizant Technology Solutions (December 2016 – November 2017)

- Utilized Microsoft Excel VBA software to track and analyze data.
- Optimized data collection procedures and generated reports on a weekly, monthly, and quarterly basis.
- Used advanced Microsoft Excel to create pivot tables and pivot reporting, as well as use VLOOKUP function.

#### **Education**

B.Tech [Electronics & Communication] - Lovely Professional University [2011-2015]

## **Professional Certificates**

Certification of Master Microsoft Excel Macros and Excel VBA [2020 – Online Course Udemy] Certification of Django Web Development [2020 – Online Course Udemy]

#### **Personal Details**

Date of Birth: 02-09-1992

Local Address: Mohiuddin Nest, Telecom Layout Nagavara, Bangalore, India Permanent Address: Village Kumbhi, Post Kumbhi, Akbarpur, Kanpur Dehat

Language Known: English & Hindi